Hey everyone and welcome.
みなさん、こんにちは。
Today we're going to dive deep into one of the most common and maybe one of the most
今日は、英語の中で最も一般的で、 誤解されやすい部分、I-N-Gの単語について深く掘り下げます。
misunderstood parts of English, the I-N-G word.
見た目はシンプルですよね？
It looks simple, right?
でも、実は秘密のルールがあります。
But trust me, it has a secret rule that, once you know it, is going to completely change
それを知ると、文の組み立て方が 完全に変わります。
how you build your sentences. So let's start with a little puzzle.
では、少しパズルから始めましょう。
Look at this sentence. The girl playing in the yard is Jane.
この文を見てください。「庭で遊んでいる女の子はジェーンです。」
Now what's this sentence really about?
この文の本質は何でしょう？
Is the main point that she's playing?
彼女が遊んでいることが主なポイントですか？
Or is the main point that her name is Jane?
それとも、彼女の名前がジェーンであることですか？
You know, the core of the sentence is actually just the girl is Jane.
実は文の核心は「女の子はジェーンです」だけです。
So what is that whole middle part, playing in the yard, doing there?
では、「庭で遊んでいる」という部分は何をしているのでしょう？
That's the puzzle we're here to solve.
これが解決すべきパズルです。
And that's what I call the ING puzzle.
これを私はINGパズルと呼んでいます。
It feels like these words can just move around wherever they want in a sentence, but they
これらの単語は文の中で自由に動けるように見えますが、実際には
can.
そうではありません。
There's a really simple, elegant rule that tells them exactly where to go, and we're
非常にシンプルで優雅なルールがあり、 それがどこに行くべきかを教えてくれます。
about to break it all down.
これからそれを詳しく見ていきます。
But to really get the secret, we have to start with a quick refresher on something
しかし、秘密を理解するためには、 みんながよく知っている形容詞についての復習が必要です。
we all know pretty well, adjectives.
これを基礎を築く作業と考えてください。
Think of this as building our foundation.
さて、形容詞の第一のルールは何でしょう？
Okay, so what's the number one rule of adjectives? It's super simple.
とてもシンプルです。
They describe nouns, right?
名詞を説明しますよね？
They just give us more information about a person, a place, or a thing.
人、場所、物についての情報を 追加してくれます。
Words like big, small, cute, or expensive. Easy stuff.
「大きい」「小さい」「かわいい」「高い」などです。簡単ですね。
And here's the crucial part. Where do they usually go?
そして重要な部分は、 通常どこに置かれるかです。
Almost always they pop up right before the noun they're describing.
ほとんどの場合、 説明する名詞の直前に現れます。
We say a big dog. We don't say a dog big.
「大きな犬」と言いますが、「犬大きい」とは言いません。
We say a cute cat, not a cat-cute. This position is key.
「かわいい猫」と言いますが、「猫かわいい」とは言いません。 この位置が重要です。
Remember that. Alright, now for the twist.
覚えておいてください。さて、ここからが面白い部分です。
This is where it gets interesting.
ここからが興味深いです。
Let's look at how that familiar ing word can secretly have two jobs and how it can
お馴染みのINGの単語が 実は二つの役割を持ち、形容詞のように振る舞うことを見てみましょう。
act just like a simple adjective.
このスライドがその秘密を明らかにしています。
This slide right here basically reveals the secret.
進行を追ってみましょう。まずはシンプルに、「猫」です。
Just follow the progression. We start simple, the cat.
次に、みんなが知っている形容詞を追加します。「かわいい猫」です。
Now let's add an adjective we all know, the cute cat.
「かわいい」がどこにあるか見えますか？次はステップ3です。
See where cute is? Now look at step 3.
「眠っている」という単語を同じ位置に入れます。「眠っている猫」です。
We take the word sleeping and slot it into the exact same place, thus sleeping cat.
突然、INGの単語が普通の形容詞のように振る舞っています。
All of a sudden, that ING word is behaving just like a regular old adjective.
公式な文法用語では、これを現在分詞と呼びます。
Now, if you want the official grammar term, this is called a present participle.
でも、その名前に惑わされないでください。
But don't let that fancy name fool you.
現在形とは関係ありません。
It has nothing to do with present tense.
進行中の、能動的な状態についてです。
It's all about an ongoing, active state.
猫は何かをしている状態です。それは眠っています。
The cat is actively doing something. It's sleeping.
つまり、現在分詞は 名詞が今何をしているかを説明するI-N-Gの単語です。
So a present participle is just an I-N-G word
さて、最初の部分を理解しているか確認するために、 簡単なチャレンジをしましょう。
that's describing what a noun is doing right now.
これらの単語を並べ替えて正しい文を作ってください。
All right, time for a quick challenge
考える時間をあげます。
to see if you've got this first part down.
「boiling」というINGの単語はどこに置くべきでしょう？
Unscramble these words to make a correct sentence.
はい、正解は「boiling water is hot」です。
I'll give you a second to think about it.
見てください、「かわいい猫」や「大きな犬」と同じように、 単独のI-N-Gの単語「boiling」は
Where does that ing word boiling need to go?
説明する名詞の前に来ます。
And there you have it, boiling water is hot.
それは「水」です。簡単ですよね？
See, just like cute cat or big dog, the single I-N-G word boiling
しかし、これが本題に繋がります。 「boiling water」が正しいなら、
comes right before the noun it's describing,
なぜ最初の文は「庭で遊んでいる女の子」だったのでしょう？
which is water, simple enough, right?
なぜINGの部分が名詞の後に来ることがあるのでしょう？
But this leads us to the main event. If boiling water is correct,
それが、私たちの友人たち、 位置の秘密のルールです。
then why was our very first sentence, the girl playing in the yard?
このスライドがその全ての秘密を 完璧に示しています。
It all comes down to one simple question.
すべては一つのシンプルな質問に集約されます。
Is the ING word alone or did it bring some friends?
INGの単語は単独なのか、それとも友達を連れているのか？
If it's just one single word, like sleeping, it goes before the noun.
もしそれが「sleeping」のように一つの単語なら、名詞の前に置きます。
But, if it has extra information with it,
しかし、追加情報がある場合、
it's friends, like in the sun,
それは友達、例えば「in the sun」のように、
then the entire group, the whole phrase, moves to come after the noun.
その場合、全体のフレーズが名詞の後に移動します。
One word goes before, a phrase with friends goes after.
一つの単語は前、友達を持つフレーズは後です。
That's it, that's the secret. So, armed with this new rule,
これが秘密です。この新しいルールを持って、
let's go all the way back to the beginning.
最初に戻りましょう。
The girl playing in the yard is Jane.
庭で遊んでいる女の子はジェーンです。
Now we have the key to unlock this thing. So, let's break it down.
これでこの問題を解く鍵を手に入れました。分解してみましょう。
The word playing isn't alone, is it? Nope, it has friends in the yard.
「playing」は一人ではありませんよね？ いいえ、庭に友達がいます。
And because it's a whole phrase,
そして、これは全体のフレーズなので、
the rule says it has to come after the noun it's describing,
ルールによれば、説明している名詞の後に来なければなりません。
which is the girl. And just like that, the puzzle is solved.
それが「girl」です。こうしてパズルは解けました。
Okay, let's practice this new part of the rule to make sure it sticks.
では、この新しいルールの部分を練習して、定着させましょう。
Unscramble these words. And as you do, think about that ing word.
これらの単語を並べ替えてみてください。そして、その際にINGの単語を考えてください。
Does speaking have any friends with it? You got it.
「speaking」には友達がいますか？ その通りです。
Look at the boys speaking English.
英語を話している男の子たちを見てください。
The word speaking has a friend English,
「speaking」という単語には「English」という友達がいるので、
so the whole phrase, the whole package,
全体のフレーズが名詞の後に来ます。
comes after the noun it's describing, the boys. See how that works?
それが「boys」です。これがどう機能するか分かりますか？
You know, once you really get this rule of position,
この位置のルールを本当に理解すれば、
it's like you've unlocked a new grammar superpower.
新しい文法のスーパーパワーを手に入れたようなものです。
You can start building sentences
より描写豊かで
that are so much more descriptive and elegant.
エレガントな文を作り始めることができます。
Let's do a quick final review. Okay, so summary number one.
では、最後のレビューをしましょう。まずは要約その1。
When your ING word is all by itself, just one word,
INGの単語が単独の時、ただの一つの単語、
it acts like a simple adjective.
それはシンプルな形容詞として機能します。
And that means it goes before the noun.
つまり、名詞の前に置かれます。
Think the sleeping cat, the singing woman, boiling water,
「the sleeping cat」「the singing woman」「boiling water」、
the rising sun, it's clean, it's direct. And summary number two,
「the rising sun」、これはクリーンで直接的です。要約その2、
when your ING word brings its friends along to the party,
INGの単語が友達を連れてくると、
the entire phrase moves to go after the noun.
全体のフレーズが名詞の後に移動します。
Things like the boys speaking English, the man swimming in the sea,
「the boys speaking English」「the man swimming in the sea」、
or the girl running with a dog.
または「the girl running with a dog」。
This is how you add all that rich detail
これが、文を絡ませずに豊かな詳細を加える方法です。
without getting your sentence all tangled up.
では、実際のポイントです。これはただの退屈な文法ルールではありません。
So here's the real takeaway. This isn't just some boring grammar rule.
より良いコミュニケーションのためのツールです。
It's a tool you can use to communicate better.
位置の秘密を知った今、
Now that you know the secret of position,
あなたはそれをどう使いますか？
the question is how are you gonna use it?
自分の文をどれだけ明確に、
How many of your own sentences can you make clearer,
より描写豊かで力強くできますか？試してみてください。